<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on Shan Islam</title>
    <link>/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on Shan Islam</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 15:36:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Python</title>
      <link>/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 15:36:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/python/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Table of Contents  Pandas  Pandas Conditonal Column  Applying functions to Pandas columns  Converting strings to date or datetime     Pandas Pandas Conditonal Column A conditional column is a column in a dataframe that is generated based on other column/s. There are multiple way of doing this in Python but one of the quickest ways is to use the np.where() function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>G1 Climax</title>
      <link>/2017-10-23-g1-climax/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017-10-23-g1-climax/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a post that is slightly different to the other posts that I&amp;rsquo;ve done so far. Rather than having a step by step tutorial on how to do something. The below allows me to work on my python skills and explain a few things as I go along.
People who work in Data Science tend to work in programming languages R or Python. I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning both languages over the last two years and at the moment I&amp;rsquo;m trying to get better at my Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pip install guide[Mini-Post]</title>
      <link>/2017-06-03-pip-install-guide-mini-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017-06-03-pip-install-guide-mini-post/</guid>
      <description>I will get back to the SQL posts but thought I would post something that could be useful to others. If you want to use Python for Data Science you will need additional python libraries.
I don&amp;rsquo;t have a huge understanding of command line functions and I found it a bit difficult to find a step by step guide on how to install python libraries .
My wife(the doctor) thought that PIP was something else medical related from a scandal a few years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>